

Minal Sudhir Misal Technical Lead

### **Contact Details:**

Mobile: +91-7709014912

**E-mail**: minalmisal7@gmail.com

### Address:

B-404, Greenlands, Opposite SNBP International School, Rahatani, Pimple Saudagar, Pune - 411017

## About Me

Technical Lead having around 10 years of IT industry experience encompassing a wide range of skill set, roles and industry verticals. Has extensive experience in developing Web Applications using .Net framework. Had past experience of working directly with clients and stakeholders at different client location in UK and in Europe. Having experience in Financial Services industry for 4+ years and E&U industry for 1+ years and rest in others.

**Hobbies:** Singing, Listening Music, Playing Badminton

DoB: 27<sup>th</sup> July 1982 LinkedIn Profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/minal-misal-61485723

## Skills & Experience Areas

- ASP.NET / C#
- ASP.Net MVC
- Entity Framework
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Angular JS (learning)
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Microsoft Windows Communication Foundation (WCF)
- Web Services (SOAP)
- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Microsoft Visio
- Microsoft VSO
- Microsoft Visual Studio Team Foundation Server (TFS)
- GitHub
- HPE Quality Center

## Education

Course: B.E. in Computer Technology

Passing Year: 2004

Institute: Nagpur University, India

## **Professional Certifications**

\* ITIL 2011 - Foundation

\* Microsoft Dynamics Customization and Configuration in CRM 2013

## Experience

Feb 2017 – Till date

Mindtree Ltd, INDIA

**Role: Technical Lead** 

### **Device Selling Platform**

Worked as Technical Lead to manage and develop Device Selling Platform for ODM and OEM partners for US client. It's an application developed in ASP.Net MVC / C# which has main application and its related downstream applications. Tools and Technologies used are ASP.Net MVC / C#, Javascript / JQuery, MS SQL Server 2014, Azure, SSIS, SSRS, VSO, Skype business (for communication)

### Responsibilities:

- Involve in developing and maintaining application and development is done using Agile scrum methodology. Estimation and sizing is done for the defects and user stories planned in the sprint.
- Involve in gathering and understanding the requirements for the user stories, clarify the requirements.
- Responsible for designing and developing technical approaches.
- Maintain the technical documents like impact analysis document and build the code as per the details mentioned in the User stories.
- Create the SQL script for deployment for the DB related changes.
- Perform unit testing of the changed functionality and verify the develop functionality is working throughout the application. Provide Test support.
- Provide demo and make the necessary enhancements for the given feedback.
- Perform technical code review for the peers to verify the coding standards are met.
- Participate in daily stand-up meetings and provide the updates to the management on the sprint progress. Also participate in all the scrum meetings
- Manage the team, assign the task to the team and track the team activities related to application development
- Involve in merging the code the and generating deployment builds
- Prepare the deployment plan for every release.
- Responsible for an on-time and quality delivery by the team as well as individual.
- Handling the team of size 14

### **Supply Chain & Audit Management**

Worked as Technical Lead to manage and develop the supply chain and audit management application for one of the "Environment Health and Safety" client from UK. It's an application developed for environment health and safety monitoring. Travelled to Cambridge, United Kingdom from 12/03/2017 to 12/04/2017 as Technical Lead on Business visa for knowledge transfer and led the transition. Co-ordinated with SME for Knowledge Transfer and stakeholder. Tools and Technologies: VS 2015, ASP.Net, C#.Net, Javascript / JQuery, Ext-JS, Oracle 11G, GIT, SVN, Rally, Slack (for communication)

### Responsibilities:

- Involve in developing and maintaining product related to Environment Health and Safety domain using ASP.Net / C#.Net and used JavaScript / JQuery for client side coding and Ext-JS for UI as per the functional specifications
- Enhance the knowledge in the other technologies i.e. Ext-JS framework
- Development is done using Agile scrum methodology. Estimation and sizing is done for the defects and user stories planned in the sprint. Each sprint is planned for two weeks.
- Responsible for designing and developing technical approaches.

- Maintain the technical documents like functional specification document, impact analysis document, Code review documents.
- Involve in preparing user manuals with illustrations for configuring development environment as well as technical understanding document of the product module.
- Involve in trainings and implementing new processes and technology.
- Involve in gathering and understanding the requirements for the user stories, clarify the requirement with Product owners and prepare the impact analysis document for review and build the code as per the details mentioned in the User stories.
- Involve in debugging the application to simulate the defects and modifies the code to fix the issues.
- Perform unit testing of the changed functionality and verify the develop functionality is working throughout the application. Provide Test support.
- Provide demo to the Product owner and make the necessary enhancements for the given feedback.
- Perform technical code review for the peers to verify the coding standards are met.
- Participate in daily stand-up meetings and provide the updates to the management on the sprint progress.
- Also participate in sprint planning, sprint review, retrospective and HIP planning meetings
- Manage the team, assign the task to the team and track the team activities related to application development
- Responsible for an on-time and quality delivery by the team as well as individual.
- Handled team size of 7 8

### Oct 2014 – Jan 2017 Accenture Services Pvt. Ltd. INDIA

**Role: Software Engineering Team Lead** 

### **Invoicing system**

Was Team Lead to support the customized Invoicing system for client Lindorff from Finland which was developed in ASP.Net MVC using domain driven design pattern. LIS invoicing system was a system to follow accounts receivables and handle activities related to receivables which is a registry where company's invoices are being followed at customer level. Worked at client location in **Finland between 3rd Oct 2015 and 7th Nov 2015** for application transition. After successful completion of transition, worked at **Accenture, Lodz - Poland from 5th Dec 2015 till 8th Aug 2016** for the service delivery in LIS application. Technologies used were VS 2013, ASP.Net MVC, Oracle SQL Developer, JavaScript, JQuery, WCF, GITHub.

## Responsibilities:

- To managed all the AM and AO activities and assignment to the team.
- Handled the team size of 4-5 and provided timely guidance.
- Performed Impact analysis and Estimations for the new business requirement.
- Managed different stakeholders to meet the business need.
- Participated in meetings and provided timely updates to management.
- Performed incident management and daily AO activities.
- Was involved in performance improvement and service delivery improvement planning.
- Created knowledge base articles for the team members which contained the technical processes to be followed in resolving the particular incidents which helped in quick resolution.

# Role: Software Engineering Team Lead Wagon Tool

Was Team Lead to develop the Wagon Tool for client – Total from France. It was a web application developed in ASP.Net to be used to order the wagon and the approval system at level of defined roles. The application was integrated with SAP. Fetched the data from SAP and presented it on UI

dynamically. Tools and Technologies used were VS 2010, ASP.Net, SAP, JavaScript, JQuery, and Ajax. Joined the project during the critical phase and ensured timely and quality delivery which was highly appreciated by management and client.

### **Responsibilities:**

- To lead the application development and integration with SAP.
- Handled the team size of 3-4.
- Helped the team to resolve the technical issues.
- Coordinated with onshore counterparts for the functional requirements to be implemented as per the business need.
- Handled the code publishing and deployment to different environments.
- Participated in daily meetings and timely provided the build updates to the management team.
- Provided Test support SIT / UAT.

#### Jul 2011 – Sept 2014 IBM India Pvt. Ltd., INDIA

## Role: Technical Lead – Microsoft Personal Loan - Point Of Sale (PLPOS)

PLPOS was personal loan point of sale web application developed in .Net technology for client Nationwide Building Society from UK. Was application team lead for transition of PLPOS application for which worked at client location in **UK from Feb 2013 till Oct 2013.** Later continued to work in the PLPOS application as Team Lead from offshore and developed the team. Got the appreciation from SME (Analysis & Design team) as well as from higher management for the roles & responsibilities performed and commitment shown towards the work and this achievement was also got highlighted in the client Newsletter. The application delivery in the project was done by partially following the scrum framework. Technology used were Asp.Net, C#.Net, Web services, WCF, XML, SQL Server 2005/ 2008, JQuery, JavaScript. TFS, VS 2005 / 2010, QC for defect management, Enterprise library.

### Responsibilities:

- Performed Application transition and shared the status on progress of the transition with the management in meetings.
- Co-ordinated with SME for the transition.
- Prepared daily and weekly reports on transition.
- Prepared the transition documents.
- Performed analysis and estimations for the change request or new enhancements
- Performed code development in PLPOS application for defects fixing or new enhancements.
- Performed the peer code review.
- Involved in creating release notes, release planning, resource profiling, and preparing release definition document from build perspective.
- Managed different stake holders involved in each release cycle.
- Also was involved in maintaining the performance matrix.
- Handled team size of 3 4

### Asset Refresh (DISE):

Technical Lead for Lower Environment migration project. Tools used are Visio, RPM, Remedy Tool. **Responsibilities:** 

- Understood the scope of servers and application and shared the scope with the team members as per the discussion on Project Plan.
- Planned the analysis of applications and preparation of the context diagrams of applications which were in scope.
- Tracked the application analysis done by the team members.
- Addressed the issues raised by the team at initial level in order to complete the analysis on time.
- Arranged for the meeting with management and brought the issues and challenges that

team is facing to them in order to take necessary action.

- Prepared the tracker to track of the team on their assigned task and target dates.
- Proactively arranged the KT calls for the team with the Onsite team members who were previously involved in the Production Application Migration which helped the team to migrate the lower environment.
- Successfully migrated approx. 100 servers in 4 months without a single rollback.
- Performed analysis of different applications to migrate the Lower environment servers from one data center to other.
- Performed analysis of application servers from hostname and domain name migration perspective which were already in new data center.
- Coordinated with different stakeholders like AM teams to perform the analysis and HCL team during migration.
- Prepared the required documents for migration such as analysis documents, cutover documents, etc. Coordinated with HCL team during migrations.
- Handled team size of 10

### Sep 2010 – July 2011 Wipro Technologies., INDIA

Role: Senior Software Engineer

### **Trade LOB**

Was Senior Developer in the maintenance of the Trade LOB which was developed in .Net technology in Securities domain for the client Schwab from US. It was a maintenance project. Partially used the scrum framework in the project. Technology used were ASP.Net, C#.Net, TFS, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Windows, Web service and VS 2005/2008.

### Responsibilities:

- To analyze the defect / change request and perform code changes to resolve them.
- To perform the defect fixing raised in testing of previous release, development of ongoing release as well as defect analysis & estimation for defect fixing which could be accommodated for next release.
- Attended daily scrum meeting and provided status of assigned works and planning for future.
- Provided SIT, UAT, MVT and RVT support.
- Updated the documents like Software Requirement Specification document, Software Design document, etc. for whatever changes in the requirement was happened.

### Nov 2008 – Feb 2010 Inspire Bridge Technologies Pvt. Ltd., INDIA

### **Role: Senior Software Developer**

Was Team Lead to develop web applications related to Ginning Management, Real Estate and Property Monitoring. Technologies used were ASP.Net, VB.Net, C#.Net, VSS, JavaScript, Ajax, MS SQL Server 2005 and VS 2005/2008.

## Responsibilities:

- To understand the business requirement and its functionality overall, design & develop the product as per the requirement. Performed development to build the application.
- Performed client interaction in order to develop the enhancement in the product specific to the client. Performed research and development to add new features to the products' functionality as per client's request.
- Conducted client Demos and based on the feedback received performed the enhancement in the product.
- Handled the team and assigned the task of development and tracked the activities assigned to team members.
- Attended daily meetings, and provide team status on the assigned work.
- Created test cases and performed unit testing. Provided SIT support.
- Provided support for the products defect fixing, enhancement, resolving performance issue.

## Early Career

Dec 2004 - May 2006 JNARDDC, Nagpur, INDIA

Role: Project Associate